all right so one of the biggest pet
peeves that I have about the go language
in some of the standard libraries is the
way people write their interface
documentation and what I'm showing you
right now is the documentation that I
use my technique of doing this is
there's a few other people that have
done this in the past I've seen them but
and I I want to show you the contrast a
little bit so you can see the difference
right away when I see the documentation
here I see a little summary and then I
have the the actual interface so I can
see what what the interface is and
particular if You' got more than one you
should usually only have one or two
methods but in this case like file info
you know there's more than one so and
and then the the the longer winded
documentation comes down below and in my
this is something that I do but I'll add
a summary of each of the interface
actions um so that you can actually go
ahead and I I'm in the middle of doing
that so here I am like writing it right
now right so this is what it looks like
but I mean this is a really big block of
documentation right so what is the
alternative to this and why do I do it
this way the May reason I do it this way
is because of the reason I just said I
can exit out of here so this is me this
is another little trick trick here if
you don't know this trick this is a way
for you to test whether your struck
implements an interface while you're
developing it uh and then you can
comment that out and then it'll it'll
it'll show you whether whether you fail
to implement that that's a a separate
little thing if I if I actually
commented any of these out uh if I Chang
the name of them this for example uh
this will start to fail because they'll
say oh you're not implementing driver
anymore because you don't have all the
methods right separate tip a separate
video on that but um and I save it and
I'll get it but but like you know if
you're writing if you're writing a
driver or you're writing an
implementation of interface you
frequently want to probably pull up the
interface so this is actually a really
great way to develop against an
interface is you create a struct you
create a little technique like this to
say it implements the interface and then
you can go back to this line and do
capital K and pull up the interface
definition and read about the contract
that you have to fulfill with the
methods and what they how they need to
perform and everything while you're
doing it and then you can go back um if
you if you're in the middle of it you
might want to you know actually another
reason uh to have that sort of summary
at the top is if you have t-o or
something like it I mean you could make
a tool to do this or you could just use
t-mo and then go bam and then grab a
couple interfaces out and exit it out
and go back to um to to pasting those in
with t-o and now you can paste your
signatures in or something but you
actually don't need to do that um it is
fun but you you don't have to do that so
that's a quick technique for um the
reason for doing that um I promise you
if you look around hard enough you'll
see people that do this instead they
will have you know they'll have like I'm
just I'm going to do one of them so you
can see how messed up this is um let's
take the let's take well let's you take
the
clear let's take the three lines of
clear Dock and put those in front of
clear so this there's lots of standard
libraries that do this um and I
absolutely detest
it um and let me let me show you why I
don't like it um so by doing it this way
hey how you doing so by doing it this
way someone argue oh it's like written
right there by the thing but this makes
it very hard to to see the interface
when you're doing the editing over here
so and most of the time honest to God I
don't need to see all the details I only
want to look at them if I need him I
just want that little summary so I'll go
to driver again let's go look at it now
and whoa wait what just
happened did I not
save what just happened what just
happened something is happening my
friends what what driver is it pulling
in that that is
weird LSP didn't update you
think
interesting what is going
on you think I need to exit and then
reopen yeah I've been finished loading
pack packages okay yeah oh God that was
weird yeah okay there we go oh my
God please no please don't do it that
way if you spend enough time programming
go you will run into this kind of inline
documentation that is just a pain in the
ass to digest you want to see as a
developer I want to see exactly what's
happening and I want a short summary so
I'm going to rest my case at that point
and I'm immediately going to delete this
back out of here because we also learned
that the LSP doesn't update unless you
restart the computer I mean the the
editor which makes sense um but annoying
right so I'm not against like one line
of documentation in here so you can get
a nice quick idea of what it does but
then you can and there's nothing wrong
with putting the big long stuff here
right you can leave it there just just
uh you know just do it that way and then
you get this nice oh God look at how
beautiful that is it's like so pretty
it's like all organized at the top and
then I can zoom down here if I want to
read more about it it's it's absolutely
perfect uh typescript the inline comment
gets picked up by the LSP which calls
the function is the same
ago do not know do not know that I wish
I had answer that's all for that video